hl7.org 2019-06-18

# Privacy Policy | HL7 International

### Overall Policy

HL7 is committed to respecting the privacy of its members and visitors, and this policy has been created to protect your privacy online, provide transparency into how and why we use your data, and to keep your data safe. With regard to personal data HL7 strives to ensure:

  * That we have legitimate grounds for collecting and using personal data;
  * That we do not use the data in ways that may have unjustified adverse effects on the individuals concerned;
  * That we are transparent about how we intend to use the data and give individuals appropriate privacy notices when collecting their personal data. 

### Notice and Disclosure

HL7 uses information collected online to keep its members and visitors aware of HL7 activities and events. We ask interested parties to furnish their contact information so we can share free information such as newsletters, conference or seminar details, publications and membership information. HL7’s bylaws require that notice of a ballot be communicated to members, and HL7 notifies members of such events primarily by email. 

### Information Collected

Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you as an individual, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, credit card information and password. We may collect personally Identifiable Information from you when you make a purchase, register to become a member, respond to an HL7 survey, voluntarily provide it when you use one of our sites or communicate with us, or voluntarily join a mail list server or chat system to contribute or request information on an HL7-related topic.

In all cases, HL7 will only collect information in accordance with legitimate interests. We collect personal data from individuals in the course of their participation in HL7 activities and events and will only use it in a manner that is consistent with their expectation as HL7 members, participants or stakeholders.

In the course of participating at HL7, members or external parties may post comments, feedback and enhancement requests related to HL7 standards or activities. HL7 is an ANSI-accredited standards development organization, and the maintenance of records related to HL7 ballots is a necessary element of ANSI compliance. Thus individuals participating in ballot activities should use caution when submitting comments, since maintaining an accurate and auditable record of all such actions is a necessary element for ANSI compliance, and may not be retractable. 

### Choice/Consent

HL7 does not make any personally identifiable information available to any unrelated third parties. However, HL7 members, as well as online registrants, do receive information from HL7 about activities that HL7 is involved with, as a benefit of their participation.

### HL7 Website Cookies

Cookies are information files that are placed onto the hard drive of your computer by your browser. Cookies allow websites to remember users activities and visits to a site. At HL7, cookies are used so that you do not have to login each time that you access the website. The cookie is used to verify your membership status, which is used to control access to “members only” documents. We do not use cookies to store or gather personal information from our visitors. You can disable cookies on your computer by indicating this in the preferences or options menus in your browser. For more information about cookies see [[http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)].

### External Links

Links to third-party websites from the HL7 website or Wikis are provided solely as a convenience to you. Using these links will direct you away from the HL7 website. We have not reviewed these third-party sites and do not assume responsibility or control for any of these sites, their content, or their privacy policies. HL7 does not endorse or make any representations about them or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to an HL7 site, you do so at your own risk.

### Commitment to Data Security

HL7 is committed to maintaining the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place reasonable procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect and store online. We use encryption technology when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. This information is used to process membership event fees or purchases of HL7 merchandise or services and is not used for any other purpose. HL7 will not resell or distribute your confidential information to any third party.

### Acceptance of Privacy Policy

If you use the HL7 website or mailing lists, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, and we will have the right to use your information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this Privacy Policy, you can choose to not access or use our services and to discontinue use of HL7 websites, Wikis or other resources. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of the Site after we either personally notify you or generally post such changes on the site will constitute your acceptance of those changes.

###  Data Quality and Access

HL7 strives to comply with applicable policy regulations and to maintain current and accurate data. If you have any comments, questions or concerns about any of the information in this Policy, corrections, or any other issues relating to the Processing of User Information carried out by us, or on our behalf, please contact:

Health Level Seven International  
Attention: Legal & Privacy  
3300 Washtenaw Ave, Suite 227  
Ann Arbor, MI 48104-4261
